Taha Mousavi

Senior Product Designer

Portfolio: <u>tahamousavi.github.io</u> Email: <u>taha.mousavi@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin: *Taha Mousavi*Phone: +989127766700

ABOUT ME

In 10 years, I've worked as the first and sole product designer in the most successful startups in Iran like; <u>Divar</u>, <u>TAPSI</u>, <u>Torob</u>, and <u>Porsline</u>.

After working as a multi-disciplinary designer and designing products used by millions of Iranian people, I am eager to work with international and multicultural companies to learn more about other cultures and nations and design products with and for them.

EXPERIENCE

Porsline, Director Of Product Design, 2021 - Present

After a successful lunch in July 2017, I have rejoined Porsline in 2021 to lead product design. Porsline is a SaaS company for creating online surveys, which helps companies in market research, customer experience research, and employee surveys.

- Adapting products for lunch in the Middle East countries.
- Branching design to the market research team to improve the products for more diverse users and new business demands.
- Deciding on the design process and user research methods.

Porsline Website

Torob, Senior Product Designer, 2020 - 2021, Contracted

Torob is a shopping search engine that allows users to find the best price of products in online stores in Iran. I joined Torob startup and directly worked with the Founder, CTO, and 4 Engineers to redesign products.

- Redesigning overall interfaces of the Torob website and Android app.
- Creating two revenue streams by redesigning core experiences.
- Developing a data-driven approach in product design.
- Improving UX by several A/B tests.

Torob Website, Torob app on Google Play

Miare, Senior Product Designer, 2018 - 2021

Miare is an on-demand delivery solution for restaurants. As the sole designer in the startup team, I designed the interface and experience of four products from scratch; Restaurant web app, Courier android app, and two web panels for live fleet monitoring.

From the first days, we had a problem-solving mindset, did several usability tests, and got a data-driven approach to product design. During four years, I have done these jobs:

- Designing four products from scratch on web and android platforms.
- Creating several prototypes for user research.
- Planning several usability tests for evaluating design ideas.
- Deciding on the UX methods and design process.
- Communicating with other teams and getting feedback.

Miare Website

TAPSI, Product Designer, 2017 - 2018

My role at the Tap30 startup was designing MVPs and prototypes of passengers application.

- Designing UI and UX of passenger and driver app.
- Planning and performing tests for evaluating design ideas.

TAPSI app on Google Play

Porsline, Product Designer, 2016 - 2017

Porsline is a SaaS startup for building forms and surveys. We designed and developed MVP by Founder, CTO, and two engineers for six months and successfully lunch the product.

- Designing prototypes for user and market research.
- Designing UI and UX of a SaaS product from scratch.
- Successful lunch of product.

Porsline Website

Divar, Product Designer, 2015 – 2016

As the only designer in Divar, I was responsible for the design of all client-side products. I worked with PMs and engineers to improve the users' experience and create consistency in the user interface on all products.

- Redesigning interface of iOS, Android, and web app.
- Evangelizing user experience design and data-driven approach to product design.
- Improving user experiences on the iOS app by gathering and analyzing data.

<u>Divar Website</u>, <u>Divar app on App Store</u>, <u>Divar app on Google Play</u>

Cafe Bazaar, Product Designer, 2014 – 2015

I was responsible for user interface design, visual design, and Front-End Development of the Aada product. I worked directly with PM to make prototypes, do usability tests.

ViraTech Sharif, UI Designer, 2012 - 2014

I designed the user interface of two Android apps and two web apps.

SKILLS

- Designing high-fidelity interface with Sketch, Figma, and Axure.
- Planning and performing Usability Test and User Interview.
- Working experience with different UX and research methods: A/B Test, Persona building, Field Study, Journey Mapping, Writing User Stories, Surveys.
- Analyzing data with Amplitude, Google Analytics, and Microsoft Excel.
- Designing Prototype with inVision, Principle, and Framer.
- Product and task management with Jira, Trello, GitLab, and ClickUp.
- Working experience with Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and Procreate for visual design.
- Web development with HTML and CSS.
- Familiar with declarative user interface development like React and SwiftUI.
- Familiar with Processing language and Generative Art.

EDUCATION

Sharif University of Technology,

Master of Science, Aerospace Engineering, 2009 - 2011

Civil Aviation Technology College,

Bachelor of Science, Aircraft Maintenance Engineering, 2005 - 2009

PUBLICATIONS

"The Effect of Small Scale on the Pull-in Instability of Nano-Switches Using DQM" International Journal of Solids and Structures, 2013, Citation Indexes: 61

"Nonlinear Dynamic Analysis of SWNTs Conveying Fluid Using Nonlocal Continuum Theory" Structural Engineering and Mechanics, 2018

COURSES

Human-Computer Interaction at Coursera, UC San Diego, The Design Lab

Creative Programming at Coursera, Goldsmiths, University of London